Guide to the Pi Alpha Xi, Cornell Chapter records, 1923-2005.
Pi Alpha Xi, Cornell Chapter records, 1923-2005
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Pi Alpha Xi, Cornell Chapter records, 1923-2005.
37-6-3492
Pi Alpha Xi.Cornell Chapter.
4.1 cubic ft.
Minutes, by-laws, publications, photographs, plaque, and scrapbooks
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes minutes of meetings, by-laws, publications, photographs, plaque, and scrapbooks of the Cornell Chapter.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Ornamental horticulture honorary association.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes minutes of meetings, by-laws, publications, photographs, plaque, and scrapbooks of the Cornell Chapter.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Pi Alpha Xi.; Cornell University--Societies, etc.; Cornell University--Students.; New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences--Societies, etc.
Subjects:
Ornamental horticulture--Societies, etc.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Minutes: Alpha Chapter Pi Alpha Xi, 1923-1939 (Box 1)
- Ledger: Financial Statements, 1923-1940 (Box 1)
- Ledger: Membership Dues, 1932-1940 (Box 1)
- Secretary's Book of the Floriculture Club of Cornell, 1937-2004 (Box 1)
- Course 115-Physiology and Biochemistry of organ Formation and Growth, 1955-1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Courses-Bibliographies (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Course Information-Bibliographies (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Floriculture 550-Student papers; Bibliographies (Box 1, Folder 4)
- "A List of the Nurseries" January, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Defoliation-Treatments, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "Famous Trees"-Parts I, II(incomplete), III (Box 1, Folder 7)
- A. M. S. Pridham: Papers and Articles, 1943-1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Pridham: Projects, Surveys, Reports, 1960's (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Pridham: Projects, Surveys, Reports; "A Letter to Young Farmers", 1950's (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Pridham: Projects, Surveys, Reports, Soil Map of Orleans County, NY, 1930's-1940's (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Pridham: Projects, Surveys, Reports, n. d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Pridham: Projects, Surveys, Reports; Floriculture 117, n. d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Pridham: Projects, Surveys, Reports; Floriculture 119, n. d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- "Proposed Market Agreement for Nursery Stock.", July 11, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- "Nursery Notes", 1941-1955 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- "Nursery Suggestions," Correspondence, Notes, 1930's (Box 1, Folder 17)
- "Nursery Suggestions," Correspondence, Notes, 1930's (Box 1, Folder 18)
- NYS Nurserymen's Association-Reports, Surveys, 1955-1962 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- New York State Nurserymen's Association-Constitution, Bylaws, January 17, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- NYS Nurserymen's Association-Miscellaneous Reports, Notes, Correspondence, 1934-1951 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Thesis: "Effects of Some Foliar Sprays, February, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- "This and That"-F. A. Pearson, January 4, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Weed Control Research, 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Banquet Menus-Programs-Certificate #1, 1923-1937 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Committee Reports, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Fraternity Lists (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Ritual of Pi Alpha Xi, Initiation Ceremony-Constitution, Original Signed Copy, Contains Names of Charter Members (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Michigan State University, Delta Chapter (Box 2, Folder 5)
- National Chapter-Minutes of Convention, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Notices of Meetings, 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Early Organization Information, 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Proposed Revision of Bylaws, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Receipts, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Report of Ways and Means Committee on Alumni Finances, December 6, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Resolutions on Deaths (Members) (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Special Meeting, October 15, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Uncollectible Accounts and Transfers to Other Chapters, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- The Lotus Leaf-Vol.1 No. 1, December 20, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- The Lotus Leaf, June 1, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- The Lotus Leaf, June 1, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- The Lotus Leaf, June 1, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- The Lotus Leaf, June 1, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- The Lotus Leaf, June 1, 1930-February 1, 1940 (Box 2)
- The Lotus Leaf, 1941-1975 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- The Lotus Leaf, Gamma Chapter, December 1, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- The Lotus Leaf, Beta Chapter, May 1, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Propagation: Articles, Notes, Reports, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Propagation: Articles, Notes, Reports, 1955-1959 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Propagation: Articles, Notes, Reports, 1954-1959 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Scholarships, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Scholarships-Faculty Approvals, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Scholarships-Faculty Recommendations, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Scholarships-Those Available and Financial Aid, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Scholarships-Letters to Recipients, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Scholarships-Recipients, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Scholarships-Letters to Donors, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Scholarships and Awards, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Scholarships-Those Available and Financial Aid, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Scholarships-Faculty Recommendations, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Scholarships-Recipients, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Scholarships-Letters to Recipients, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Scholarships-Faculty Recommendations, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Department Scholarships and Awards, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Scholarships-Letters to recipients, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Scholarships-Letters to Donors, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Scholarships-Senior Awards, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Scholarships and Awards, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Scholarships, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Approval for Senior Awards, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Approval for Senior Awards, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Scholarships and Awards, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Department Reception for Seniors, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Scholarships and Awards, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Senior Awards-Faculty Suggestions, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Jack Lander Memorial Award, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- New York State Cemetery Association Award, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Outstanding Freshman Award, May 9, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Outstanding Freshman Award, 1960-1969 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Herman R. Schenkel, Sr. Memorial Award, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Senior Awards, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Lewis Sperber Memorial Award, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Sperber Award, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Sperber Award-Applications, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Sperber Award-Applications, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Sperber Award-Environmental Industries, Inc.;Photos, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Nor-am Chemical Company Scholarship, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Arthur Thomas Memorial Award, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Joseph J. Yedowitz, Sr. Memorial Award, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Pridham Materials: Film, Program, Map of Cambridge (UK), n. d. (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Nursery Stock and Supply Locator, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- "Home Grounds: Their Planning and Planting" Text Prepared by L. H. Bailey, 1918 (?) (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Miscellaneous Programs, Brochures, 1956, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- "What is Horticulture?" By Prof. L. H. Bailey, 1905 (?) (Box 3, Folder 44)
- "Words Said About A Birthday" Delivered at Cornell University, April 29, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- "My Great Oak Tree and Other Poems" By L. H. Bailey, September 8-10, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Pre-Cornell and Early Cornell IV; Biology at Cornell University 1868-1928, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- The Eighth Annual Farmers' Week, February 8-13, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- "A Century of Growth" Meadow Brook Nurseries, 1845-1945, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 49)
- "The Floriculture Life", January, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- "The Floriculture Life", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 51)
- "The Floriculture Life" Graduation Issue, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Pre-Cornell and Early Cornell VIII, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Pre-Cornell and Early Cornell IX, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- "Mechanization Needs of the Nursery Industry" (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Yearbook of the Horticultural Society, 1924-1925 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Various Publications, 1929, 1961, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Acceptances, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Bylaws-Revised and Adopted, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Class Lists, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- General Meeting Information, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Graduate Faculty, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Graduate School Information, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- "History of Pi Alpha Xi"-Brochures, n. d. (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Honorary Members, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Initiation Ceremony, n. d. (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Letters to Candidates, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Membership Letters, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Membership and Mailing Lists (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Membership Lists, n. d. (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Membership List-Jewelry, 1965-1969 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- New Members, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- New Members, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- New Members, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Newspaper Clips-Correspondence, 1943-1946 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Obsolete and Outmoded Ritual (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Pi Alpha Xi-Constitution (Original and Superceded) (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Pi Alpha Xi-Newsletter, 1933-1944 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Pi Alpha Xi-Newsletter, 1933-1944 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Ritual of Pi Alpha Xi-Chaplain's Copy, 1925, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Sample Letters, 1975-1989 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Correspondence, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Correspondence, 1933-1934 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Correspondence, 1950-1961 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Correspondence, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- 1976-1977, Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Correspondence, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Correspondence-Pi Alpha Xi National, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Correspondence, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Correspondence-Invoice Receipts, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Correspondence, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Correspondence, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Correspondence, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Correspondence, 1985-2004 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Correspondence, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Correspondence, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Correspondence-Class Lists, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Correspondence-Class Lists, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 54)
- Correspondence, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 55)
- Correspondence, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 56)
- Correspondence, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 57)
- Correspondence, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 58)
- Correspondence-Pi Alpha Xi National, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 59)
- Correspondence-Catalogs-Newsletters, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 60)
- Correspondence-Pi Alpha National Meeting, Montreal, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 61)
- Correspondence-Curtis, R. W., 1940-1945 (Box 4, Folder 62)
- WHAM-1180-Correspondence, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 63)
- Pi Alpha Xi Freshman Award Plaque (Box 5)
- Minutes, 1939-1978 (Box 6)
- Membership lists, 1939-1990 (Box 4)